Yeah, that that that was my first pop
tart
in my existence like we don't have that
in Europe.
Yeah, they they don't they don't allow
that [__] in Europe. That's that's pure
American poison right there.
All right, y'all hold up for just a sec
cuz we've all heard of living off the
land as a red teamer technique, right?
Well, unfortunately, I just got off a
call with the threat locker team and
they said that isn't going to fly
anymore thanks to the ring fencing
feature. Let me double click on that for
you, okay? Think of ring fencing as like
an invisible fence around your
applications. As soon as an application
interacts with some app or system
resource that it normally doesn't, bam,
it gets blocked. Even if that thing is
native to the OS like powershell.exe or
certutil.exe.
So, yeah, rip living off the land. Back
to the drawing board for the red team, I
guess. Anyway, if you want to see this
in action, head over to threatlocker.com
for a demo and when you do ask for my
guy Andrew. His demo was very to the
point and he had great answers to all my
technical questions. Check it out,
y'all. Seriously, don't sleep on threat
locker, especially not in this recent
landscape of EDR uncertainty. Am I
right? Yeah, I'm right. Okay, y'all
know. All right, let's get back to the
show.
All right, Ronnie, dude.
What a day, man? Am I right? Yeah, man.
That was the day. That was the day. It
was indeed and yeah, it is late. It is
what? 11:00 and we are still recording a
pod for you guys cuz we love you.
Um
and this beautiful
thing right here that is sitting in
front of us for those of you that are
not watching, I'm sorry, but this is the
Google bug swat MVH trophy that your
boys won. I'm so freaking happy, man.
Yeah, dude, that was that was a
wonderful event. Um shout out to the
Google team. It was really awesome and
whenever we have sort of events like
this,
um I kind of want to just do a little a
bit of a deep brief, right? Of course.
So, uh let's see, where do I want to
start? Um
once again, we kind of go straight to
the main app, right? That's a part of my
methodology. I don't know if that's as
much a part of your methodology, but
it's somewhere I'm very comfortable,
right?
And uh I think that that has a lot of
value.
Um but it doesn't always pan out because
uh a lot of times in the targets that
we've been facing recently, there's been
ways to affect main scope, you know,
tier zero scope um by going
around. So, I've been thinking more
lately that I kind of want to start
doing that again, but this event once
again reinforces the upsides of just
going straight for the main target. So,
how did you feel about that this event?
Yeah, um
I feel like uh we
like the Google team faceted everything,
so we could actually hack on the main
target.
Um during the scope call, they explained
to us uh the entire application and uh
we really went in depth about how uh it
was impacting the business and that's
something that I really like to
understand uh all the business impact of
a vulnerability,
uh how I can bring value to the table.
And not only they told us about all the
past vulnerabilities that brought value
where they found it, but also like,
"Hey, if you bypass that, this is a huge
vulnerability." And so, you know, when
we hear that, we want to find that
again. Yeah, it's massive when the
company helps you with threat modeling,
right? Because I think one of the first
steps and actually I really liked how we
both intentionally did that this event
where we we spent some time getting to
know the application, right? Getting
familiar with the scope. And then we we
sat down and we just looked at each
other and we're like, "How do we attack
this thing? Like, okay, we can come from
this direction with prompt injection or
we can come from, you know, this place
or the other place, that sort of thing."
Um and that ideation, I think, over the
course of the
uh
over the course of our hacking on this
target, uh led us to the right path
pretty quickly, right? Um cuz we only I
think
I mean, you did a little bit of hacking
before, but uh because of various like
family things and travel plans that I
had and H1 live hacking event, I only
had like three or so days to hack on
this target.
Um but we were still able to get a
really good result and I think that's
because of thorough threat modeling done
by the Google team and also by us. Uh
more than that, like I know that you
like to talk about technical, but to be
honest, it's because that guy never
takes any break. Uh that's the reason we
got MVH. Oh my gosh, dude. Well, I had
to tell you so many times, "Now we are
going on a break, Justin." Well, that
that has value, too, right? Because like
I was, you know, burning the burning the
midnight oil, you know, I was hacking
till like 1:30 or so after having done
DEF CON and other competitions and
stuff, but um
you know, the times when you said, "All
right, Justin, go get food. Justin, go,
let's walk around. Justin, let's sit
here and talk about the attack vectors
and get reoriented." That really helps
and I think that also played into the
collaboration, so
um
really good stuff there. Uh I think
isn't it the first time that we
Yeah, no, it's the second time that we
collaborate like fully on the target.
Like uh and we pass all the time that we
have on this
Google, right? Yeah, both Google.
Man, I I think by the day like this
collaboration really worked well because
like we have like some different style
of looking uh at something and also of,
you know, managing our time or uh
mindset
of hacking. I know that sometimes you
like to go on a laser focus and go all
the way until we find the vulnerability
and sometimes I like to take back things
and just say, "Okay, let's
put back context to what we are doing
and try to understand, isn't there like
an easiest path?" And
those techniques are really different,
but at the same time it's like the two
face of
uh of a coin, right? They complete each
other. Yeah, that definitely. And I
think that really helped us uh because
at I I one time we were like, "We need
to go deep into that technique." And
that's where we found like
we're under NDA for most of it and we
hope that we can disclose that one day,
but uh we we found like the first uh
attack vector that we reported and it's
because like you wanted to dig deeper
and we couldn't let you do anything
else, right? Yeah, yeah. That that was
definitely huge and I think also um just
going back to that as well,
you know, regarding context and versus
like laser focusing and going deep and
deep and deep.
A lot of times in fully black box
scenarios, you have to kind of do that
by intuition and by a feel. Um but with
the Google live hacking events,
something is really different from any
other live hacking event that I've
really participated in and that is that
Google engineers, some of the smartest
people in in in tech, will sit Yeah,
seriously, will sit next to you with
their laptops and like go through code
and like
talk through your attack vector with you
at a very knowledgeable level. And these
are people not that um
you know, are are on the security team
and like, you know, do security stuff
but don't really touch the code. These
are like
I say, "Here's the functionality." And
like within 5 minutes, they have
narrowed down all of the Google code
base to that just just that
functionality and you're looking at the
correct function, which is just
an amazing skill, but also I think
speaks to Google investing
uh a lot of time and effort into their
code search tools
um and then weaponizing, you know,
really equipping their engineers to know
how to use that effectively.
Um and I think that is something that
will
that contributed to us being able to
find a really really solid bug on a very
short timeline.
And I think what also really helped is
that Google mindset is that
hunters are the extension of the
security team, right? We we we're not
two separate entities. We are trying to
do the same job and so they are going to
go all the way to help us actually pop a
creed. And
that speaks a lot about how they see the
industry and how they value
uh bug hunters. And I feel like more
companies should give that trust. And I
don't know like if Google is in position
to do that because they are Google or
just because like the security team are
just a bunch of great human beings, you
know.
Well, actually I think I was talking to
some of the Googlers about it and I
think it's also because they have a good
lawyer
uh associated with their with their team
that's semi-technical, right? That
understands the the requirements of what
needs to be happening and kind of makes
that happen, right? So, I think that's a
huge piece and I I know that a lot of
organizations don't have access to that
and probably won't have resources to do
that, but I feel really privileged to be
able to participate in a Google live
hacking event where we do have that
privilege. Um and we can see, you know,
the bolstered effect of that happening
there.
Um yeah, so all right, let's go from
there to some of the technical stuff.
Obviously, we're under NDA for a lot of
stuff, but I think we can talk about
overarching principles and because
Google's pretty good with uh disclosure,
I think we should be able to
uh talk about
more technical details in the future. Um
but
let's just say, as always, anytime you
are able to run code in a sandboxed
environment, that needs to be thoroughly
checked. And not only does it need to be
thoroughly checked on the front of uh
can we escape the container? Can we
um you know, do some sort of super
technical exploit that will allow us to
break out or is there a misconfiguration
in the container? But also um on the
front of what kind of things are being
put into that container and how can we
weaponize the various services that are
exposed there to accomplish malicious
goals. Because sometimes that container
is locked down as can be, but there's an
API sitting right outside or like you
know, a port sitting sitting open on an
adjacent host that can really make all
the difference.
Yeah, like
you know,
when life throw you like a bunch of
you know, tools that are like not useful
at all, you need to do something with
it. You need to build something with it.
And basically when you are in the
sandbox environment and maybe you are
not like
the kind of hunter that know all the
sandbox escaping in the world.
guy, dude. Yeah, I am
I'm a web guy, too. And I I don't I
don't know how
really how to
escape on a sandbox. That's not
something I'm want to look at. But like
we basically looked at one another. I
just say, "Okay, what's what's inside
the sandbox?" And because also the
Googlers told us like, "Hey,
you should check what's inside the
sandbox because sometimes we don't even
know what's happening there."
Yeah.
Yeah, I think I think that's big. I
think that's really big. And I think
going after targets you're intimidated
by as well is necessary and something
pretty much every time I've been proud
of
the performance that I've had at a live
hacking event, it's been when I've gone
after a target that I was intimidated
by. Um
so that's that's big.
Yeah, that that's actually as I'm saying
it to you here on the pod, I am
realizing that that needs to be like a
core tenant of my scope selection from
now on is like what is the most
intimidating part of this app?
What is the thing that is going to be
hard for me to hack or that I need to
learn stuff about and then going after
that. I think that will that will pay
dividends a lot of times. And like we
ran into in this situation, there were
many things that we didn't know how they
worked, you know?
We were looking at a lot of code that we
weren't familiar with, the the language,
the structure, the the the linting rules
that they have. It's like whack how
things are formatted. But um
yeah, we we kept on pushing through all
that and and I think we we got a result
that we're that we're proud of. I really
like what you're saying here because
that's something that really resonate
with a lot of time
my mindset. But at the same time I think
I'm not applying it too much. But it's
that our comfort zone is the same as so
many other people comfort zone.
Yeah, web is web is
web is debatable the easiest to learn, I
think. But even with our hacking like
our comfort zone is
you know, the same as so many people
comfort zone. And when you try to step
out, you will go to unexplored places.
And that's where research truly starts.
It's not like when we take a methodology
and just apply it and see if it works.
It's when you don't have any cue about
what kind of methodology you are going
to use. You are going to the scary stuff
and you are going to get scared. Like I
think if it wasn't for you doing the
collab, I would have just say, "Ah, no,
it's too hard." But you were like, "No,
we need the next step." And then I was
like, "Oh, okay, but we can do that."
And
yeah, we we pushed one another and
that's what we helped us, I think, go
out of this comfort zone. And because
also each of every step was so funny.
Like
Yeah, oh man, it was great. Yeah,
there's some the product we're hacking
is very
there's there's some very
humorous outcomes on that, which is
which is really good. Um the other
technical piece that I or a couple two
more technical pieces that I wanted to
bring in is
a trend that I've seen across multiple
live hacking events now, which is that
there are often some really really good
bugs in the SDKs for the targets that
we're looking at, right? Like if you if
you're targeting an application, fine,
go hack that application. But often
times there's ways for customers or like
collaborators, I don't I don't know what
to say that, like associated companies
to utilize part of the code in
like sort of an integration, right? With
the app that you're hacking on. And
those are and not just an integration in
the sense of like, "Oh, you go into the
web panel and you link your account."
which often does have problems, but
that's not what I'm talking about right
now. What I'm talking about is more of
code exposed that
that the target application wants their
customers to run on their machines to
integrate correctly with with this app,
right? And I think time and time again
we've seen really impactful ones there.
One because a lot of people just focus
on the main web app and don't go after
the SDKs, but um
but also because when you can tell a
company that their code is making their
customers vulnerable,
that really freaks them out.
And often times you'll have
customers implementing the the code in a
very similar way across the board. And
if the company is large enough to be
running a bug bounty program, you often
have a very large impact surface for
those sort of things. Um so that's a
really great tip as well when it comes
to selecting a target and going towards
a little bit more of a untraditional
approach to
attacking that main application, right?
Yeah, and also on top of that like if
you can re-understand the core of the
business, you if you can leak anything,
you'll know if it's impactful or not.
And that assessment is really
re-interesting to do because like on on
previous live hacking events I've
attended, too, like
Snorlax and I found in the JavaScript
file just some description
of integration that the company was
doing with their clients.
However, those integration were totally
confidential. And so we just reported a
bunch of text that was exposed in the
JavaScript and we got paid for that. And
I guess that a lot of people would have
missed that because we don't have like
this understanding of the business. So
even if we are deep down in the
technical, we are like trying sandbox
escape and everything. And then you see
a piece of code and you are like, "Wait
a minute, isn't that something that not
supposed to be there?" And you go all
the way to look at why it's not supposed
to be there and what we could do with
that. Even it's not like a secret
credential or something like that. This
just having the business perspective
could help you to find the vulnerability
and convert like something that you
think is nothing to a "Oh, that
shouldn't be there." Yeah, I think you
do that really well, Ronnie. I've seen
you do that a couple times across
different scopes. So I think it also
reminds me of a of a scenario that I
that I ran into at a live hacking event
probably three or four years ago with
John Bottarini and he essentially was
one of his highest paying bugs of the
event was
him
showing the team how his requests could
cause extreme legal action to be taken
against them in massive fines from the
government, right? And and they were
like, "Oh, shit." You know, like it was
it was bad. And and that's just not and
that required more knowledge of policy
and how it applies to the scope, how it
applies to the application and how they
were automating, you know, the some of
these more regulated sectors. Um
for
for him to be able to to find that
vulnerability and and then on top of
that properly explain it to the
the security team and then to the legal
team as well as they became involved. So
there's lots of there's lots of I mean
there's clear PII leak, there's code
execution, there's you know, all of
these known more known traditional
classes, but I think there's also a
whole class of like vulnerabilities that
relate to legal compliance, weaponizing
GDRP, um
GDRP GDRP, thank you. It's late. Thank
you. I was like,
"GDRP, that doesn't sound right."
No, that's too European for the US mind.
Yeah,
the US mind cannot comprehend
GDRP, there we go.
Um
yeah, I I think that's a I think that's
something that requires a further
knowledge of the app which can be
attained by
using the app, reading the
documentation, doing really thorough
threat modeling. That's actually a trick
that I've used in a bug bounty to raise
the severity of certain leakage that I
had. It was just like, "Hey, can you run
this by your legal team and just tell me
what they they say to you." And
something that people do not often
realize is that in most of the
companies, the security team and the
legal team don't get along at all. And
so when the this security team at the
time asked the question to the legal
team like this was straight up race to
critical and they were like,
"Yeah, we got a huge problem now." And
like just before they were like, "Oh,
that's medium." You know? And
so that's a cool trick to just you know,
ask the legal like the security team
what's up about the legal impact because
sometimes we miss stuff about those
policies. So uh
yeah, I think that we should dig deep in
the technical, but sometime we need to
take a step back and just think about,
"Okay, what's the business impact here
and what's the legal impact?" And all
those other implications are more like I
would say human and policies, less
technical.
But I think that the way that we both
think that really helped us on our
collab.
Yeah, with that, for sure.
I think just bringing it over to the
last technical thing that I had sort of
in my head from this event as a
takeaway, which is that I think
when you think about the age of
companies as well, there's a lot of
vulnerabilities that uh
crop up more than expected. And Google's
been around for a while, you know? And
they've they've been a part of like
their code has become core and important
from very early on right in the internet
really even
and so
I didn't really think of Google like an
old product and I'm sure it's gotten
lots of code review and rewriting and
that sort of thing but I think there
were a lot of things that I saw
in this event that surprised me from a
that I would have more associated with
older companies
that cropped up on Google
and so
taking some time thinking about okay
well hey we all know that you know
PayPal and eBay and like some of these
you know older companies right just to
name a couple Google as well
they've got some janky stuff in there
and approaching it like an older
application rather than something that
is might have
modern architecture decisions even
though of course Google does but there's
also those older pieces that have to
stay around. Yeah and I kind of feel
like those companies are so big that
there so many processes in place
like technical processes you know in
order to
not screw up some part of the code base
that sometimes you just need to rely on
human error and just a logic error in
the flow so I'm not talking about like
business logic error but just like hey
what happened if this happen it's still
inside the policy of code review
compliance and everything but
it shouldn't be there
and so that that's I think an angle of
attack for those giant companies of just
trying to think about scenarios where
everything goes right because they're a
process based company but that sometimes
the process is actually the
vulnerability.
Yeah that's good.
Do you have any thoughts so those those
are my my main thoughts on the technical
pieces for the event did you have
anything that came to mind that you were
surprised about from the event from a
technical perspective
or any of the things you wanted to shout
out about the event itself? Yeah I shout
out I have
at least one in mind
I was stuck with the technical
I would say like
all the others bug hunter at this event
really astonished me
by by all of their their skill and
knowledge about the Google
infrastructure
something that I realized that the
Google bug hunters
are not that much in the scene of other
platforms and other lab hacking events
but they are so skilled
and it really astonished me like we we
we met Tom
who is the first on the Google VIP yeah
the number one the Google VIP program
and the way that if things about
vulnerabilities like he casually dropped
some some internet breaking
vulnerability and he just started the
report by oops
Yeah
Yeah that was that I know exactly what
you're talking about that was very yeah
we were talking about some research that
came out we'll keep it we'll keep it
you know under wraps but we were talking
about some research that came out
recently that we were really excited
about and then he's like oh yeah yeah I
know what you're talking about and then
he like pulls up
a report from like 2020 or 2019 yeah and
he's like oh yeah I think I found this
back then and I was like okay well why
didn't you freaking publish it you know
like like I would have loved to have
seen that you know back then and so I
mean of course there's reasons not to
but it's amazing to see what kind of
knowledge
that we just sort of assumed was not
there right until the the research was
released but there are you know
motivated actors specifically people
that are focusing
main on a specific bug bounty program or
something like that or people that just
want to keep a lower profile that
that are just just total beasts Yeah and
I really like when we had this
discussion it was at lunch and he showed
you the report and I
I would have loved to film your face
because
I actually looked at the other bug
hunters and I was like I think he broke
Justin Oh my gosh dude I was I was
tripping man you know how I am with
vulnerabilities like you see you see the
vulnerability and you're just like that
is a thing of beauty that is a thing of
awe Yeah of course and and also like one
big shout out that I want to do about
this whole event is like
that's your third MVH man Dude I yes it
is I'm excited for that so France
come get it come get it boy
I don't know if he I don't know if he
has
a non
a non hacker one MVH he might be at four
or five who knows yeah
it does feel nice it really does Yeah
man I'm so happy because this is also my
first one Dude you rocked it man it was
a great collab it was a great collab
Definitely
for for for for people like to
understand how great of a collab it was
yeah at some point it was so late at
night and because of jet lag and
everything I was just sleeping on my
keyboard like he could actually see me
sleep on my keyboard and at some point
he was like hey dude I got the next step
wake up and like we we got through it
and
and the next day he was so asleep
out
We were at the Google like they they had
like a suit at a really nice hotel and
he was just sleeping on the couch in
front of everyone Yeah dude it was it
was bad
And I think that's when I was continuing
like what he started on the research and
I think that tells a lot about our
collab but also like I would say about
our friendship and like all the trust
that we have and
I realized that
when when we doing it was just so funny
man that was so cool Yeah man definitely
definitely a wonderful collab
shout out to all the Googlers out there
Sam Erb Gabor
Jan Martin you know all of them it was a
really it was a really cool event The
the space that they held it on the
second day was really awesome too
and man the snacks there were pretty
much unparalleled like literally you
walk in there and there's like a whole
freaking king-size bed worth of like tea
size table filled with like a different
snack on each vertical row and I was
just like wow I'm like a kid in a candy
store I got got some like trail mix I
got some like
what the freak are these like little
pop-tart bites like this is it's
delicious man That was my first pop-tart
in my existence like we don't have that
in Europe you know Yeah they they don't
allow that [__] in Europe that's pure
American poison right there
All right Ronnie well thanks for I know
it's late man I yeah we're pushing it
but thanks for thanks for coming on the
pod and deep briefing a little bit with
me it was it was a really fun event I
think there's some good takeaways Yeah
and
we we can do that what whenever you want
like you know winning MVH Of course of
course all right dude good stuff
peace
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more Critical
Thinking content head over to
ctb.show/discord
join the discord there's lots of great
conversations and chats going on over
there and if you want to support the
show there's the discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes AMAs hackalong exclusive scripts
and an exclusive chat channel with us
we'll see you there